Guide to the Fiametta Olschki Papers relating to Leo S. Olschki (Firm) and Olschki family members, 1904-1994
Department of Special Collections
Olschki, Fiammetta. Papers relating to Leo S. Olschki (Firm) and Olschki family members,
1904-1994
M0739
Olschki, Fiammetta
8.75 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Includes personal family correspondence between the Wittkowers and their son, and between the Olschkis and their children. The papers of the firm include individual files of correspondence with major scholars and collectors. In addition, there is a history of the firm written by Fiammetta Olschki Witt and information about her catalogue raisonné of European travel books, 1990. Included in the papers of the firm is a file on the Serristori archive (1452-195?) with descriptions and the 1982 valuation; a political oddment file with a German anti-semitic leaflet, 1933, and student protest material from the 1960s and early 70s; and three files about the Florence flood, documenting the losses suffered by the firm, 1966-67.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Boxes 8-11 restricted until 2025.
Provenance
Gift of Fiammetta Olschki Witt, 1995 and 1998.
Biography
Leo S. Olschki was founder in 1886 of the prestigious publishing house of the same name. Fiammetta Witt née Olschki married Mario Max Witt (earlier Wittkower). She is the granddaughter of Leo Samuel Olschki, and niece of Leonardo Olschki and Cesare Olschki. Mario Witt's parents were Rudolf and Margot Wittkower.
Scope and Content
Includes personal family correspondence between the Wittkowers and their son, and between the Olschkis and their children. The papers of the firm include individual files of correspondence with major scholars and collectors. In addition, there is a history of the firm written by Fiammetta Olschki Witt and information about her catalogue raisonné of European travel books, 1990. Included in the papers of the firm is a file on the Serristori archive (1452-195?) with descriptions and the 1982 valuation; a political oddment file with a German anti-semitic leaflet, 1933, and student protest material from the 1960s and early 70s; and three files about the Florence flood, documenting the losses suffered by the firm, 1966-67.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Barbensi, Gustavo.; Beltrame, Giancarlo.; Bernini, Gian Lorenzo, 1598-1680.; Bircher, Martin.; Bonifacio, Franco.; Bononi, Loris Jacopo, 1929-; Borroni Salvadori, Fabia.; Bouffard, Pierre.; Bury, John.; Buzzanca, Giampaolo.; Chaney, Edward.; Corinth, Louis, 1858-1925.; De Marinis, Tammaro.; Fryszman, Jacques.; Heckscher, William S.; Held, Julius Samuel, 1905-; Hofmannstal, Gerty von.; Jacobi, Erwin R. (Erwin Reuben), 1909-1979.; Jaffâe, Michael, 1923-; Kissner, Franklin H. 1909-1988.; Mooser, R. Aloys.; Oakeshott, Walter, Sir.; Oechslin, Werner.; Olschki, Cesare.; Olschki, Leo Samuel.; Peyrefitte, Roger.; Praz, Mario, 1896-; Prezzolini, Giuseppe, 1882-; Saks, John A.; Sparrow, Joh Hanbury Angus, 1906-; Strano, Luigi.; Strauss, Rudolf.; Toulmin Meoli, Rachel.; Van Portengen, Lumen.; Olschki, Leonardo, 1885-1961.; Rosenthal, Robert.; Seilern, Antoine, Count, 1901-1978.; Vishniac, Roman, 1897-; Weil, Hanna.; Witt, Mario Max.; Wittkower, Margot.; Wittkower, Rudolf.; Zorzi, Alvise.; Leo S. Olschki (Firm);. 0$aBooksellers and bookselling--Italy.;. 0$aFloods--Florence (Italy);. 0$aPublishers and publishing--Italy.;. 0$aSerristori archive.
Collection Contents
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and their son, Mario, adding later their daughter-in-law Fiammetta Witt, nee Olschki. [1942-46] (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and their son, Mario, adding later their daughter-in-law Fiammetta Witt, nee Olschki. [1948-51] (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1952] (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1953] (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1954] (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1955] (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1956] (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1957] (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1958] (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1959] (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1959] (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1960] (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1960] (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1961] (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1961] (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1962] (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1963] (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1964] (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1964] (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1965] (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1965] (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1965] (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and their son, Mario, adding later their daughter-in-law Fiammetta Witt, nee Olschki. [1966] (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1966] (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1967] (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1967] (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt. [1968] (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1968] (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1968] (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1969] (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1969] (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1969] (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1970] (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1970] (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1970] (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1971] (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1971] (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Wittkower, Rudolf and Margot: Letters between them and Mario and Fiammetta Witt.[1971] (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents., [Poems] (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1938-39] (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1940] (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1941] (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1942] (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1943] (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1944] (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1944] (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1945] (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1945] (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1946] (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1946] (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Wittkower later Witt, Mario Max. Letters to his parents.[1947] (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Olschki Leo Samuel. Five letters to his son Cesare, both personal and with details about his book-buying activities. A copy of his testament dated July 5th., 1939. [1911-21] (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Olschki, Leonardo. Part of his correspondence to an from his brother Cesare. [1904-1952] (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Olschki, Leonardo. Part of his correspondence to an from his brother Cesare. [1953-1961] (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Olschki, Cesare. Letters of condolence on his death. [1971] (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Olschki, Cesare. Letters of condolence on his death. [1971] (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Olschki, Cesare. Letters of condolence on his death. [1971] (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Olschki, Cesare. Letters of condolence on his death. [1971] (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Olschki Fiammetta. Her speech on the centenary of the firm Leo S. Olschki. [1886-1986] (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Olschki Fiammetta. A singularly one-sided correspondence with the Centro Romantico which is part of the library Gabinetto Vieusseux in Florence. The Centro now owns her collection of 741 European travel books for which she made the cataloque raisonne during the years 1988 to 1990. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Olschki Fiammetta. Correspondence with the Centro Romantico. [1988-1990] (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Olschki Fiammetta. Travels in Europe, her presentation speech and a few reviews after the book was published. It must be added that she did not get a cent for her labors and that neither the director of the Centro nor the publisher, Daniele Olschki, took notice of her dispositions regarding the title nor the lay-out of the book which should have been logically disposed in chronological order. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Leo S. Olschki Antiquarian Booksellers. Letters from scholars and customers, preserved for names and contents. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Leo S. Olschki Antiquarian Booksellers. Letters from scholars and customers, preserved for names and contents. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Leo S. Olschki Antiquarian Booksellers. Missions to London to assist buying manuscripts for some of the main Italian libraries [1967-1972] (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Leo S. Olschki Antiquarian Booksellers. Missions to London to assist buying manuscripts for some of the main Italian libraries [1967-1972] (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Leo S. Olschki Antiquarian Booksellers. Missions to Perugia to assist buying manuscripts for some of the main Italian libraries [1967-1972] (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Leo S. Olschki Antiquarian Booksellers. File on the SERRISTORI archive (1452-195?). This very important archive consists of over 800 volumes, boxes and large folders of manuscript material from the XVth century to modern times. With summary descriptions of contents and an official valuation made in 1982. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Florence Flood. File with official correspondence for the Circolo dei Librai Antiquari, Fiammetta Witt being president at the time. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Florence Flood., Photographs. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Florence Flood. File with writings and photographs documenting the losses suffered by the firm owing to this shattering catastrophe. [1966-67] (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Art. Photographs and comments concerning: Bernini. A drawing with an identifying description and one drawing by Rudolf Wittkower. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Art. Photographs and comments concerning a Louis Corinth drawing, [self-portrait on both sides]. (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Art. Comment concerning a painting. Oil on wood of the Royal George. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Art. A fake autograph of a Tintoretto letter (19th century). (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Art. Comments concerning a painting by Lumen Van Portengen. (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Barbensi, Gustavo. Italian doctor who introduced the application of statistics to medicine in Italy. Author of pioneering works on medicine and medical history. 1965 to 1973., Letters. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Bonifacio, Franco. Italian politician and collector. For a time minister of justice. Corespondent with Olschki-Witt from 1967 to 1986. Part 1. (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Bonifacio, Franco. Correspondence Part 2. (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Bononi, Loris Jacopo. Author and bibliophile. Correspondence 1969-1972. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Borroni Salvadori, Fabia. Art historian, bibliographer. Published "Il Nuovo Cicognara" in 12 volumes as well as important works and articles on subjects relating to history and art-history. A friend and corespondent from 1976 to 1982, her death. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Buzzanca, Giampaolo. Dealer. Correspondence. 1965 - 1979. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Buzzanca, Giampaolo. Dealer. Correspondence. 1965 - 1979. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Chaney, Edward. Scholar. Correspondence. 1989-1990. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Chicago, University of - Rosenthal, Robert. Correspondence. 1977-1989. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Chicago, University of - Rosenthal, Robert. Correspondence.1977-1989. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Chicago, University of - Rosenthal, Robert. Correspondence.1977-1989. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- De Marinis, Tammaro. Bibliographer and high class dealer. Correspondence.1963-69. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1959-65. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1965-67. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1967-68. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1968-69. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1969. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1970. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1971. (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1972-73. (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1976. (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1976-77. (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1977-79. (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1980-82. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1982-85. (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1985-86. (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Art historian, collector of drawings, dealer. Correspondence.1987-93. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Lists of books on offer 1962-1974. Important for the history of antiquarian book prizes. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Lists of books on offer 1962-1974. Important for the history of antiquarian book prizes. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Lists of books on offer 1962-1974. Important for the history of antiquarian book prizes. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Fryszman, Jacques. Lists of books on offer 1962-1974. Important for the history of antiquarian book prizes. (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Heckscher, William S., Scholar. Correspondence 1964-65. (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Heckscher, William S., Scholar. Correspondence 1965-67. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- [Hanford, Henderson] An involved correspondence about a Soutman drawing, first attributed to P.P. Rubens. Eight ff. of references accompany two photographs. Apart from letters and post-cards to and from H. Henderson who appears here as 11 an unsuccessful trickster. The folder contains letters from Julius Held, Michael Jaffe, Count Antoin Seilern, Pierre Bouffard from the Conseil Administratif de la Ville de Geneve, a few single writings, and finally a correspondence with Sotheby's who, in the end sold the drawing. All to and from M.M. and F. Witt. (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Hofmannsthal, Gerty von. Widow of the poet Hugo von Hofmannsthal (1874-1929). A few letters to Fiammetta Olschki Witt who lived with her in Oxford during the years 1948-1950. The letters are of later date. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Jacobi, Erwin Reuben [1909-1979]. Musicologist and collector. [1968-73] (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Jacobi, Erwin Reuben [1909-1979]. Musicologist and collector. [1973-79] (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Kissner, Franklin [1909-1988]. Bibliophile and collector. Correspondence [1965-66] (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Kissner, Franklin [1909-1988]. Bibliophile and collector. Correspondence [1966-69] (Folder 16)
- Kissner, Franklin [1909-1988]. Bibliophile and collector. Correspondence [1969-71] (Folder 17)
- Kissner, Franklin [1909-1988]. Bibliophile and collector. Correspondence [1971-74] (Folder 18)
- Kissner, Franklin [1909-1988]. Bibliophile and collector. Correspondence [1974-77] (Folder 19)
- Kissner, Franklin [1909-1988]. Bibliophile and collector. Correspondence [1977-88] (Folder 20)
- Mooser, R. Aloys. Musicologist and collector. 1969. His last letter is dated August 3rd and he died on August 24th. at the age of 93. On his importance see in enclosed article "R.- Aloys Mooser et sa bibliotheque musicale". (Musees de Geneve, Avril 1972). (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Oakeshott, Sir Walter. Scholar, author. Wrote a celebrated study on the Winchester Bible. High Master of St. Paul's, Head Master of Winchester, Rector of Lincoln, Vice Chancellor of Oxford. Correspondence.1968-69. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Oakeshott, Sir Walter. Scholar, author. Correspondence.1969-70. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Oakeshott, Sir Walter. Scholar, author. Correspondence. 1971-72. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Oakeshott, Sir Walter. Scholar, author. Correspondence. 1973-76. (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Oakeshott, Sir Walter. Scholar, author. Correspondence. 1977-87. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Peyrefitte, Roger. French author and collector. Correspondence.1961-64. (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Political Oddments. A small, random collection of ephemera, in various languages, mainly Italian, going from 1933 (German antisemitic leaflet) to 1979. Includes party (any) and student appeals. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Praz, Mario. Author of many celebrated critical works on English literature. Pioneer in the study of emblems. Correspondence. 1953-80. (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Prezzolini, Giuseppe. Author, journalist, politically involved. The correspondence concerns the sale of his archive now housed in Lugano. [1977] (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Prezzolini, Giuseppe. Correspondence. 1978-79. (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Saks, John A. Bibliophile and collector. Correspondence. 1967-70. (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Saks, John A. Bibliophile and collector. Correspondence.1970-73. (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Saks, John A. Bibliophile and collector. Correspondence.1973-75. (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Sparrow, John. Author, scholar, Warden of All Souls in Oxford. Correspondence. 1962-70. (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Sparrow, John. Author, scholar, Warden of All Souls in Oxford. Correspondence. 1970-80/83. (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Strano, Luigi. Italo-Australian poet and collector. Correspondence. 1991-94. (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Vishniac, Roman. Scientist, collector, eccentric. Correspondence. 1961-63. (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Vishniac, Roman. Scientist, collector, eccentric. Correspondence.1963-78. (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1972] (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Restricted until 2025.
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1972] (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1972] (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1973] (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1973] (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1973] (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1974] (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1974] (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1974] (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1975] (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1975] (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1976] (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1976] (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1977] (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1977] (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1978] (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1979] (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1979] (Folder 18)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1980] (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1980] (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1981] (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1981] (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1982] (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1982-83] (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1983] (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1984] (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1984-85] (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1985] (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1986] (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Wittkower, Margot. Correspondence with her son, Mario, and her daughter-in-law, Fiammetta Witt. [1987] (Box 9, Folder 7)